CV: Yujie Zheng Last updated: 2021-05-18

# **YUJIE ZHENG**

Curriculum Vitae

Division of Geological and Planetary Sciences Seismological Laboratory California Institute of Technology

1200 E. California Blvd., MC252-21

Pasadena, CA 91125

Email: <u>yjzheng@caltech.edu</u>

www.yujiezheng.me

https://orcid.org/0000-0001-9013-

451X

Phone: 650-946-6358

# **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

My research focuses on developing and applying new techniques to analyze a combination of geodetic observations – primarily Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar (InSAR), to better understanding changes of the Earth's surface related to natural (e.g., active tectonics and volcanic processes, permafrost thawing/freezing) and anthropogenic processes (e.g., withdrawal of groundwater from aquifers).

## **EDUCATION**

## Stanford University, Stanford, CA

Ph.D., Geophysics, January 2020

- Thesis title: Imaging Cascadia slow slip events with modern interferometric synthetic aperture radar datasets
- Committee: Howard Zebker (principal advisor), Paul Segall, Eric Dunham, Dustin Schroeder

## Peking University, Beijing, China

Bachelor of Science in Geophysics, July 2014 Bachelor of Economics, July 2014

# **EMPLOYMENT AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE**

Postdoctoral Scholar, California Institute of Technology

Research Assistant, Stanford University

2019 – present
2014 – 2019
Undergraduate Research Assistant, Peking University

2012 – 2014

# **PUBLICATIONS**

### In preparation:

- **Zheng, Y.**, Fattahi, H., Agram, P., and Simons, M., On closure phase and Systematic Bias in Multi-looked SAR Interferometry.
- **Zheng, Y.** and Zebker, H.A., Investigating Cascadia slow slip and interseismic deformation with Interferometric Synthetic Aperture radar
- **Zheng, Y.** and Segall, P., Constraints on absolute magma chamber volume from geodetic measurements: Trapdoor faulting in the Galapagos

### Accepted:

 Wang, T., Zheng, Y., Pulvirenti, F., Segall, P., Post-2018 caldera collapse re-inflation uniquely constrain Kilauea's magmatic system, *Journal of Geophysical Research: Solid Earth*

#### Published:

- Zheng, Y., Zebker, H.A., and Michaeledes, R.J., 2011. A New Decorrelation Phase Covariance Model for Noise Reduction in Unwrapped Interferometric Phase Stacks, *IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, doi:* 10.1109/TGRS.2021.3050087
- **Zheng, Y.**, Zebker, H.A., and Michaeledes, R.J., "A Physics-Based Decorrelation Phase Covariance Model for Effective Decorrelation Noise Reduction in Interferogram Stacks," *In Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium*, 2020 IEEE International (pp. 16-19). IEEE.
- Zheng,Y., 2019, Imaging Cascadia Slow Slip Events with Modern Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar Datasets, Ph.D. Thesis, Stanford University
- Michaelides, R.J., Zebker, H.A., Zheng, Y., 2019. An Algorithm for Estimating and Correcting Decorrelation Phase from InSAR Data Using Closure Phase Triplets. *IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote* Sensing, vol. 57, no. 12, pp. 10390-10397
- **Zheng, Y.** and Zebker, H.A., 2017. Phase Correction of Single-Look Complex Radar Images for User-Friendly Efficient Interferogram Formation. *IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing*, 10(6), pp. 2694-2701
- Zebker, H.A. and **Zheng, Y.**, 2016, July. Robust and efficient InSAR deformation time series processing. *In Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium*, 2016 IEEE International (pp. 3198-3200). IEEE.
- **Zheng, Y.** and Zhou, S., 2014. The spatiotemporal variation of the b-value

and its tectonic implications in North China. Earthquake Science, 27(3), pp.301-310.

# **Invited Talks**

- Caltech Institute of Technology, Seismology lab Seminar, Nov 2020
- University of California, Berkeley, Active Tectonic Group Seminar, Oct 2018

## **CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS**

- Zheng, Y., Fattahi, H., Agram, P., Simons, M., 2021, June. Closure Phase and Systematic Bias in Multi-looked SAR Interferometry. Fringe 2021 Workshop
- **Zheng, Y.**, Fattahi, H., Agram, P., Simons, M., 2020, December. Assessing closure phase and its impact on InSAR time-series. *2020 American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting, Abstract G004-0029*
- Wang, T., Segall, P., Zheng, Y., 2020, December. Illuminating Kilauea's magmatic plumbing system: physics-based modeling of post 2018 simultaneous inflation and deflation. 2020 American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting, Abstract V002-0005
- Zheng, Y., Zebker, H.A. and Michaelides, RJ., 2020, September. A Physics-Based Decorrelation Phase Covariance Model for Effective Decorrelation Noise Reduction in Interferogram Stacks. 2020 IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium.
- Segall. P., Wong, YQ, Heimisson, ER, Zheng, Y and Anderson KR, 2019, December, Physics-based Models Expand Insights Gained from Volcano Geodesy. 2019 American Geophysics Union Fall Metting, Abstract G31A-01
- Zheng, Y. and Zebker, H.A., 2019, December. Are redundant interferograms really redundant? On the use of redundant interferograms to reduce noise. 2019 American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting, Abstract G21-04
- Zheng, Y. and Zebker, H.A., 2018, December. Slow Slip Events in Cascadia: Observation from Sentinel-1. 2018 American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting, Abstract U11B-02 (invited)
- Zebker, H.A. and Zheng, Y., 2017, June. Slow Slip Event in Cascadia: Observation and Hazard Analysis Derived from Sentinel-1 InSAR. Fringe 2017 Workshop
- · Zheng, Y., and Zebker, H.A., 2017, December. Retrieving Ground

- Deformation Associated with Cascadia Slow Slip Events Using Sentinel-1 Data. 2017 American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting, Abstract G34A-04
- Zheng, Y. and Zebker, H.A., 2016, December. Crustal deformation associated with Cascadia slow slip events from InSAR time-series, 2016 American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting, Abstract S33A-2812
- **Zheng, Y.** and Zhou, S., 2014. The spatiotemporal variation of the b-value and its tectonic implications in North China, 2014 International Workshop on Statistical Seismology.

### **FELLOWSHIPS AND AWARDS**

American Geophysics Union Outstanding Student Paper Award

The Joshua L. Soske Fellowship, School of Earth Sciences, Stanford University

### 2014

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

### **Teaching Assistant, Stanford University**

- GP90/ESS113 Earthquakes and Volcanoes, upper level undergraduate course
- EE60N/GP60N Man versus Nature: Coping with Disasters Using Space Technology, Introductory Seminar for first-year undergraduate students.
- EE355/GP265 Imaging Radar and Applications, advanced graduate course

## **ACADEMIC SERVICES**

- Reviewer for Journals Remote Sensing in Earth Systems Science, IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, Nature Communications
- Member of IEEE International Geoscience & Remote Sensing Symposium Scientific Committee
- Online Reviewer for NASA Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (EPSCoR 2017) research proposal

## **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATION**

2014 - Present: American Geophysical Union (AGU)

2016 - Present: IEEE member